Reading Task
The Sporting Robot
My name is Hua Fei, and I am a sporting robot of the 23rd century.
I am an expert at high flying exercises.
I jump from spaceships and as I fall I turn,
dive, circle and dance until I softly land as close as I can to the finishing line.
I won the silver medal for my performance.
I wanted to meet robots from other countries and explore ideas about our sport.
However, my programmer fell ill the week before we were going to leave.
It was very painful for her and I felt very frightened.
I no longer felt so confident that I would win.
The day of the competition was rather cold for my legs and my special oil began to freeze.
I paused before I jumped from the starting place on a little spaceship
but then I began my performance.
At the correct moment I tried to open my parachute but there was a problem.
It only opened a little.
Instead of flying softly to earth I began to fall faster and faster
so that I could not turn, dive,
circle or dance.
My heart stopped beating as I landed heavily on a mountain covered
with snow.
This is why I am writing to you from my hospital bed with two broken legs
and a fragile head.
I did not win anything at the Olympics after all.
I need the factory to build me two new legs and an even bigger head.
Then I will be able to compete once more.
Let’s hope for greater success in the next Olympics!